<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Class Notes on UAH Notes</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Class Notes on UAH Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-1-technology-and-the-modern-enterprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-1-technology-and-the-modern-enterprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market capitalizations:&lt;/strong&gt; The market cap of a publicly traded firm is its total value. Market cap can be calculated by multiplying the number of a firms shares by its current share price.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R&amp;amp;D:&lt;/strong&gt; Research and development—the portion of a firm focused on innovation, typically pioneering advances that will eventually arrive as new products and technologies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microprocessors:&lt;/strong&gt; The part of the computer that executes the instructions of a computer program.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server farms:&lt;/strong&gt; A massive network of computer servers running software to coordinate their collective use. Server farms provide the infrastructure backbone to SaaS and hardware cloud efforts, as well as many large-scale Internet services.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pivoting:&lt;/strong&gt; In product development and entrepreneurship, this involves significantly redefining the market, business, and/or product offering.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Term Sheet:&lt;/strong&gt; A legal document that is the agreement between a founding firm and its investors. It defines investment terms, ownership stake, board membership if offered, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Hype Cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; Innovation Trigger, Peak of Inflated Expectations, Trough of Disillusionment, Slope of Enlightenment, and Plateau of Productivity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-10--platforms-network-effects-and-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-10--platforms-network-effects-and-competition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network effects:&lt;/strong&gt; Also known as Metcalfe’s Law or network externalities. When the value of a product or service increases as its number of users expands.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platforms:&lt;/strong&gt; Products and services that allow for the development and integration of software products and other complementary goods, effectively creating an ecosystem of value-added offerings. Windows, iOS, the Kindle, and the standards that allow users to create Facebook apps are all platforms.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staying power:&lt;/strong&gt; The long-term viability of a product or service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switching costs:&lt;/strong&gt; The cost a consumer incurs when moving from one product to another. It can involve actual money spent (ex. Buying a new product) as well as investments in time, any data loss, and so forth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Complementary benefits:&lt;/strong&gt; Products or services that add additional value to the primary product or service that makes up a network.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APIs:&lt;/strong&gt; Programming hooks, or guidelines, published by firms that tell other programs how to get a service to perform a task, such as send or receive data. For example, Amazon provides application programming interfaces (APIs) to let developers write their own applications and websites that can send the firm orders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily Active Users (DAU):&lt;/strong&gt; Also known by the acronym DAU, this refers to the number of unique visitors, on average, who use a product or service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer acquisition costs:&lt;/strong&gt; The amount of money a firm spends to convince a customer to buy (or in the case of free products, try or use) a product or service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metaverse:&lt;/strong&gt; Immersive digital worlds. The term metaverse was coined by science fiction writer Neal Stephenson in his 1992 novel Snow Crash. The term has become so ubiquitous that it inspired Facebook to rebrand itself as Meta.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-sided market:&lt;/strong&gt; A market that derives most of its value from a single class of users (e.g., instant messaging).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same-side exchange benefits:&lt;/strong&gt; Benefits derived by interaction among members of a single class of participant (e.g., the exchange value when increasing numbers of IM users gain the ability to message each other).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two-sided market:&lt;/strong&gt; Network market that comprises two distinct categories of participant, both of which are needed to deliver value for the network to work (e.g., video game console owners and developers of video games).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-side exchange benefit:&lt;/strong&gt; When an increase in the number of users on one side of the market (console owners, for example) creates a rise in the other side (software developers).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monopoly:&lt;/strong&gt; A market where there are many buyers but only one dominant seller.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oligopoly:&lt;/strong&gt; A market dominated by a small number of powerful sellers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technological leapfrogging:&lt;/strong&gt; Competing by offering a new technology that is so superior to existing offerings that the value overcomes the total resistance that older technologies might enjoy via exchange, switching cost, and complementary benefits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social proof:&lt;/strong&gt; The positive influence created when someone finds out that others are doing something.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blue ocean strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; An approach where firms seek to create and compete in uncontested “blue ocean” market spaces, rather than competing in spaces and ways that have attracted many similar rivals.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convergence:&lt;/strong&gt; When two or more markets, once considered distinctly separate, begin to offer features and capabilities. As an example: The markets for mobile phones and media players have converted (and smartphones won).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Envelopment:&lt;/strong&gt; When one market attempts to conquer a new market by making it a subset, component, or feature of its primary offering.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backward compatibility:&lt;/strong&gt; The ability to take advantage of complementary products developed for a prior generation of technology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adaptor:&lt;/strong&gt; A product that allows a firm to tap into the complementary products, data, or user base of another product or service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Osborne Effect:&lt;/strong&gt; When a firm preannounces a forthcoming product or service and experiences a sharp and detrimental drop in sales of current offerings as users wait for the new item.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Congestion effects:&lt;/strong&gt; When increasing numbers of users lower the value of a product or service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exchange value:&lt;/strong&gt; The quantitative ratio at which one commodity is exchanged for another—often expressed as its price in money.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-17--data-and-competitive-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-17--data-and-competitive-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big Data:&lt;/strong&gt; A general term used to describe the massive amount of data available to today&amp;rsquo;s managers. Big Data are often unstructured and are too big and costly to easily work through via use of conventional databases, but new tools are making these massive datasets available for analysis and insight.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Intelligence (BI):&lt;/strong&gt; A term combining aspects of reporting, data exploration and ad hoc queries, and sophisticated data modeling and analysis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytics:&lt;/strong&gt; A term describing the extensive use of data, statistical and quantitative analysis, explanatory and predictive models, and fact-based management to drive decisions and actions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine learning (ML):&lt;/strong&gt; A type of artificial intelligence that leverages massive amounts of data so that computers can improve the accuracy of actions and predictions on their own without additional programming.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data:&lt;/strong&gt; Raw facts and figures.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information:&lt;/strong&gt; Data presented in a context so that it can answer a question or support decision-making.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Knowledge:&lt;/strong&gt; Insight derived from experience and expertise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database:&lt;/strong&gt; A single table or a collection of related tables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database management systems (DBMS):&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes referred to as database software; software for creating, maintaining, and manipulating data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structured query language (SQL):&lt;/strong&gt; A language used to create and manipulate databases.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database administrator (DBA):&lt;/strong&gt; Job title focused on directing, performing, or overseeing activities associated with a database or set of databases. These may include (but not necessarily be limited to) database design, creation, implementation, maintenance, backup and recovery, policy setting and enforcement, and security.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table or file:&lt;/strong&gt; A list of data, arranged in columns (fields) and rows (records).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Column or field:&lt;/strong&gt; A column in a database table. Columns represent each category of data contained in a record (e.g., first name, last name, ID number, date of birth).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Row or record:&lt;/strong&gt; A row in a database table. Records represent a single instance of whatever the table keeps track of (e.g., student, faculty, course title).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relational databases:&lt;/strong&gt; The most common standard for expressing databases, whereby tables (files) are related based on common keys.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serverless computing:&lt;/strong&gt; A type of cloud computing where a third-party vendor manages servers, replication, fault-tolerance, computing scalability, and certain aspects of security, freeing software developers to focus on building “business solutions” and eliminating the need to spend time and resources managing the technology complexity of much of the underlying “IT solution.”&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transaction processing systems (TPS):&lt;/strong&gt; Systems that record a transaction (some form of business-related exchange), such as a cash register sale, ATM withdrawal, or product return.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Some kind of business exchange.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loyalty program:&lt;/strong&gt; A system that provides rewards and usage incentives, typically in exchange for a method that provides a more detailed tracking and recording of customer activity. In addition to enhancing data collection, loyalty cards can represent a significant switching cost.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Artificial intelligence:&lt;/strong&gt; Computer software that seeks to reproduce or mimic (perhaps with improvements) human thought, decision-making, or brain functions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data aggregators:&lt;/strong&gt; Firms that collect and resell data.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legacy systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Older information systems that are often incompatible with other systems, technologies, and ways of conducting business. Incompatible legacy systems can be a major roadblock to turning data into information, and they can inhibit firm agility, holding back operational and strategic initiatives.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data warehouse:&lt;/strong&gt; A set of databases designed to support decision-making in an organization.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data mart:&lt;/strong&gt; A database or databases focused on addressing the concerns of a specific problem (e.g., increasing customer retention, improving product quality) or business unit (e.g., marketing, engineering).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online analytical processing (OLAP):&lt;/strong&gt; A method of querying and reporting that takes data from standard relational databases, calculates and summarizes the data, and then stores the data in a special database called a data cube.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data cube:&lt;/strong&gt; A special database used to store data in OLAP reporting.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data lake:&lt;/strong&gt; A catch-all term for storage and access technologies used in Big Data. Data lakes are systems that allow for the storage of data in both structured as well as “raw,” “unfiltered” formats. Data lakes also provide the tools to “pipe out” data, filter it, and refine it so that it can be turned into information.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hadoop:&lt;/strong&gt; A set of mostly open source tools to manage massive amounts of unstructured data for storage, extraction, and computation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data cloud:&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes referred to as cloud data warehousing, this term refers to a cloud service that provides tools to extract and transform data from disparate sources so that it can be interrogated as needed. Unlike data warehouses, data lakes, or similar tools that an organization might run on-site, a data cloud can be spun up to temporarily hold a very large amount of data for short-term use, then be disbanded when it is no longer needed. Snowflake is the best known of the many firms providing services in this space.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ETL:&lt;/strong&gt; Extract, Transform, Load—copying data from multiple, disparately organized data sources, transforming (or cleaning) the data into a common format, and loading it into a combined usable format. ETL is a key step in getting data into a data warehouse or data mart.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Query tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Tools to interrogate a data source or multiple sources and return a subset of data, possibly summarized, based on a set of criteria.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python:&lt;/strong&gt; A general purpose programming language that is also popular for data analytics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;R:&lt;/strong&gt; A programming language specifically created for analytics, statistical, and graphical computing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphical query tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Tools that allow a user to create a query through a point-and-click or drag-and-drop interface, rather than requiring programming knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Canned reports:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports that provide regular summaries of information in a performative format.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ad Hoc reporting tools:&lt;/strong&gt; Tools that put users in control so that they can create custom reports on an as-needed basis by selecting fields, ranges, summary conditions, and other parameters.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dashboards:&lt;/strong&gt; A heads-up display of critical indicators that allow managers to get a graphical glance at key performance metrics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data visualization:&lt;/strong&gt; The graphical representation of data and information.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generative AI:&lt;/strong&gt; A type of artificial intelligence whose output is some type of media: e.g., text, images, audio, video. Results are usually generated based on a prompt, such as typed or spoken text. This technology “learns” the patterns and structure of data used during training, and can then generate new output based on the characteristics of this input. Results can often be refined by further prompt entry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Omnichannel:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing customers with a unified experience across customer channels, which may include online, mobile, catalog, phone, and retail. Pricing, recommendations, and incentives should reflect a data-driven, accurate, single view of the customer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data mining:&lt;/strong&gt; The process of using computers to identify hidden patterns in, and to build models from, large datasets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over-engineer:&lt;/strong&gt; Build a model with so many variables that the solution arrived at might only work on the subset of data you’ve used to create it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-18--artificial-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-18--artificial-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;182-generative-ai-whoathis-is-something-different&#34;&gt;18.2 Generative AI: Whoa—This Is Something Different!&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#182-generative-ai-whoathis-is-something-different&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;AI has been around for many years&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goal of AI is to create computer programs able to mimic and improve on human intelligence&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ChatGPT 3.5 release in fall 2022 accelerates AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most user-accessible version of AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First real accessible &lt;strong&gt;generative AI&lt;/strong&gt; (to the general public)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gen AI &lt;strong&gt;prompted&lt;/strong&gt; by user&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can also make up wrong answers and provide them to a the user-&lt;strong&gt;Hallucination&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Public release of ChatGPT controversial and created a debate on the consequences of AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;OpenAI investment increases dramatically after the release of ChatGPT (Microsoft)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;183-so-how-does-this-stuff-really-work-a-managers-guide-to-understanding-genai&#34;&gt;18.3 So How Does This Stuff Really Work? A Manager’s Guide to Understanding GenAI&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#183-so-how-does-this-stuff-really-work-a-managers-guide-to-understanding-genai&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../assets/image_1762072119972_0_1762457848696_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;image_1762072119972_0.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corpus&lt;/strong&gt; data used to train a model&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supervised learning&lt;/strong&gt; - supervised training by providing specific result examples&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Supervised learning&lt;/strong&gt; - data is not explicitly labeled and results are not preditermined&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Humans examine LLM feedback at many major firms&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;184-generative-ai-changing-products-and-the-nature-of-work-itself&#34;&gt;18.4 Generative AI: Changing Products and the Nature of Work Itself&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#184-generative-ai-changing-products-and-the-nature-of-work-itself&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Generative AI synthesizes information in large organizations, helps with creative work and brainstorming, etc.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also helps with education, training, quality improvement&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Real time coding assistant&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pair programming improved&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Graphic design work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Office productivity tools&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;New Office 365&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Accounting&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Help corporate tax departments&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Legal Work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Goldman Sachs predicts that AI might make up 44% of legal work&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could have an issue where AI cites cases that do not exist (Hallucination)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;185-understanding-ai-risks&#34;&gt;18.5 Understanding AI Risks&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#185-understanding-ai-risks&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Developing rapidly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could be issues with the data that is fed into AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prompt injection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;data poisoning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bias with the technology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hallucinations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;((690714b0-3dfe-46d2-aa81-7558963505a2))&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ethical implications&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Students using AI and passing it off as their own&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Journalists passing off AI-generated content as their own&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can cause harm&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Copyright and AI is uncertain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Job loss&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scale of AI concentrates power and carries enviromental impact&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can be destructive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Could maybe not understand how it is operating&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;186-its-not-as-easy-as-the-press-might-state-technical-organizational-legal-and-societal-challenges-of-ai-and-machine-learning&#34;&gt;18.6 It’s Not as Easy as the Press Might State: Technical, Organizational, Legal, and Societal Challenges of AI and Machine Learning&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#186-its-not-as-easy-as-the-press-might-state-technical-organizational-legal-and-societal-challenges-of-ai-and-machine-learning&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Issues that managers might encounter with AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data quality- inconsistent data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Data security&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not enough data&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Training required to manage AI&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Identify processes that need to be changed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Machine learning types that are legally prohibited&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Unintended consequences of data misuse might lead to regulation and limits on technology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Additional privacy issues as the increased amount of communication&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Certain firms may be able to gain advantage in the market and therefore collect more data -&amp;gt; Generate data -&amp;gt; Create predictions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;187-addressing-airisks-and-building-more-responsible-technology&#34;&gt;18.7 Addressing AI Risks and Building More Responsible Technology&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#187-addressing-airisks-and-building-more-responsible-technology&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Increased oversight of ethical challenges and artificial intelligence&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;steps-in-developing-more-ethical-less-risk-prone-systems&#34;&gt;Steps in developing more ethical, less risk-prone systems&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#steps-in-developing-more-ethical-less-risk-prone-systems&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hire diversely&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hire ethicists&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Develop a code of technology ethics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a systems review board&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create and enforce technology audit trails&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Partner to build better technology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Partner to build better technology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Develop and refine clear employee policies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Implement strong tech and procedural training programs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gather and act on input regarding flaws&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Provide a means for remediation&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Test and audit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Continually evaluate best practices and incorporate proven techniques&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roll out new technology gradually&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-2--zara/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-2--zara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Initially wished to be called Zorba but there was a bar already with that name in his town&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Therefore had to rearrange the letters that had already been cast into Zara&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Not the name that makes the business but rather the technology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The company is now part of Inditex Corp&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The firms crown jewel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Headquartered in Spain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Crushed the performance of rival H&amp;amp;M&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zara has many stores throughout the world&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Manhattan and Shanghai, among others&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-study-zara&#34;&gt;Why Study Zara&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why-study-zara&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Competitors are faltering&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zara is undergoing one of the fastest global expansions the fashion world has ever seen&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Most innovative and devestating retailer in the world&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physical retailers are struggling-but Zara is not&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Super efficent model&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Higher margin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Competitive prices&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fewer markdowns and write-offs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Faster inventory turnover&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Reduced risk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Less advertising&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://resized-images.flatworldknowledge.com/information_systems_9_1-36477/1600/information_systems_9_1-36477-fig097.png&#34; alt=&#34;The rapid growth of Inditex&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gap-an-icon-in-crisis&#34;&gt;Gap: An Icon in Crisis&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#gap-an-icon-in-crisis&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most fashion retailers place orders for a seasonal collection months before in stores&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inventory = Death&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Having too much unwanted product on hand and you will be forced to mark down or write off items&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gap made a bad bet on what would attract customers and strayed from the classic styles that it was known for&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Was saddled with inventory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contract Manufacturing&lt;/strong&gt; in developing countries can keep the cost of goods low&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lower prices and sell more product&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Race to the bottom in cost cutting measures&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Increasing accusations of using sweatshop labor&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bangladesh has a bad reputation for unsafe worker conditions in factories&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tech can be used to identify companies that have unsafe or sub-standard labor practices (Rebook) or dishonest manufacturers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-guess-gather-datamake-small-batches-of-what-customers-want-and-ship-it-fast&#34;&gt;Don’t Guess, Gather Data—Make Small Batches of What Customers Want and Ship It Fast!&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#dont-guess-gather-datamake-small-batches-of-what-customers-want-and-ship-it-fast&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zara operates off of increasing data collection&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Custom apps on mobile devices to collect data from customers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Looks for left behind items by customers and works to analyze trends&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Insights go back to headquarters&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salaries are based off of store sales performance&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10% of the firms overall profit increase is shared across firm employees&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Point of Sale system used to  tally up sales and deduct the sold items from inventory&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whats selling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What customers at a given location want to see on shelves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Plan new styles and issue rebuy orders&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#design&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zara designs follow trends&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#39;book-hint &#39;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Our business model is the opposite of the traditional model. Instead of designing a collection long before the season, and then working out whether clients like it or not, we try to understand what our customers like, and then we design it and produce it.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-2-sample-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-2-sample-questions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  In a company where manufacturing overhead is applied based on machine hours, the predetermined allocation rate is $3 per machine hour. Actual machine hours were 3,000 and actual manufacturing overhead was $8,000.&#xA;  &#xA;  Is overhead underallocated or overallocated and by how much?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1,000 overallocated&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Jones Company is a consulting firm and applies indirect overhead costs based on billing hours. The firm expects to have $75,000 in indirect costs during the year and bill customers for 7,500 hours. The cost of direct labor is $55 per hour.&#xA;  &#xA;  What is the predetermined overhead allocation rate for Jones Company?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 per hour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  When direct materials are used in production, costs are assigned by debiting Work-In-Process Inventory and crediting ________.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Raw materials inventory&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  The cost of goods manufactured for the period is $100,000.  &#xA;  &#xA;  The journal entry to record the transfer of the finished goods to a storage area before being sold would be:&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Accounts&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Debit&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Credit&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Finished Goods Inventory&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;100,000&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;Work-in-Process Inventory&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;100,000&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The journal entry to record goods that are finished but not yet sold is &lt;strong&gt;a debit to Finished Goods and a credit to Work-in-Process Inventory&lt;/strong&gt; for the cost of goods manufactured.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Brooks Company is a consulting firm and applies indirect overhead costs based on billing hours. The firm expects to have $75,000 in indirect costs during the year and bill customers for 750 hours. The cost of direct labor is $55 per hour.&#xA;  &#xA;  Brooks Company completed a consulting job for George Peterson and billed the customer for 15 hours. What was the total cost of the consulting job?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The predetermined allocation rate is equal to estimated indirect labor costs/estimated billing hours = $75,000/750 = $100 per hour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Amount billed is equal to (direct labor cost per hour + $100 per hour for indirect costs) x 15 hours $2,325 = ($100 + $55) x 15 hours&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Jones Company has an overallocated amount of $2,000 after balancing the Manufacturing Overhead account.&#xA;  &#xA;  The debit entry to close out the overallocated amount would be ________.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Manufacturing overhead&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  White Company manufactures furniture. Assume the following information:&#xA;  &#xA;                  &#xA;  &#xA;  Manufacturing overhead is allocated based on machine hours.&#xA;  Manufacturing overhead is estimated to be $150,000 and machines hours are expected to be 10,000 hours.&#xA;  The actual manufacturing overhead is $31,000 and there are 2,000 actual machine hours.&#xA;  How much manufacturing overhead would White Company allocate?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../assets/image_1763535007323_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;image.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Cost of Goods Sold is considered what type of account?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Equity-expense account&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Acme Consulting uses job order costing to determine the cost of services provided to clients.&#xA;  &#xA;  For a particular year, Acme has budgeted the following amounts:&#xA;  The firm has completed job 101 for a client. Job 101 involved 25 hours of direct labor. Acme assigns indirect costs based on direct labor hours. What is the cost of job 101?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;| Office rent and utilities | ﻿$100,000 |&#xA;| ﻿Support staff | ﻿$70,000 |&#xA;| ﻿Advertising | ﻿$25,000 |&#xA;| ﻿Supplies | ﻿$5,000 |&#xA;| Direct labor (based on 2.000 hours)  | ﻿$120,000 |&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  The journal entry to allocate manufacturing overhead costs to production would include a credit to ________.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Manufacturing Overhead&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  Thompson Company is a consulting firm and applies indirect overhead costs based on billing hours. The firm expects to have $7,700 in indirect costs during the year and bill customers for 700 hours. The cost of direct labor is $60 per hour.&#xA;  &#xA;  Thompson Company completed a consulting job for Joe Lock and billed the customer for 20 hours. What was the total cost of the consulting job?&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Estimated indirect labor costs / Estimated hours&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;$11 per hour = $7,700/700&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-20--a-managers-guide-to-the-internet-and-telecommunications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-20--a-managers-guide-to-the-internet-and-telecommunications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#introduction&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Internet is a business enabler&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Marketers who have an understanding of the internet and its impact on consumers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Understanding how the internet works helps the manager to assess how their firms are vulnerable&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep their organization constantly connecting&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;internet-101-understanding-how-the-internet-works&#34;&gt;Internet 101: Understanding How the Internet Works&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#internet-101-understanding-how-the-internet-works&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The internet is a network of networks&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Your local network (intranet) connects to the Internet service provider to access the wider internet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is no center to the internet, no one owns it&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Therefore is extremely fault tolerant&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Arose from military and education institutions work as far back as the 1960s&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Took off in the 1990s when graphical browsing was invented&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Architecture was then transitioned to private firms rather than government grants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://resized-images.flatworldknowledge.com/gallaugher_7-32630/1000/gallaugher_7-32630-fig127.png&#34; alt=&#34;Example network diagram showing the connection between local networks (intranet) and the larger internet&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-url-what-are-you-looking-for&#34;&gt;The URL: “What Are You Looking For?”&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#the-url-what-are-you-looking-for&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;URL (uniform resource locator)&lt;/strong&gt; - Used interchangeably with &amp;ldquo;Web Address&amp;rdquo;, URLs are used to identify resources on the Internet along with the application protocol needed to retrieve it&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Basically used to tell your browser what you are looking for&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;      The URL displayed really says, “Use the Web’s secure SSL protocol (https://) to find a host server named ‘www’ in the ‘nytimes.com’ network, look in the ‘tech’ directory, and access the ‘index.html’ file.”&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://resized-images.flatworldknowledge.com/information_systems_9_1-36477/1000/information_systems_9_1-36477-fig109.png&#34; alt=&#34;A breakdown of a URL&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hypertext transfer protocol&lt;/strong&gt; - Application transfer protocol that allows web browsers and Web servers to communicate with each other&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most sites now use https instead of http&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shift occurred aggressively several years ago&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warning shows up if not secure&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;https is achieved by using &lt;strong&gt;SSL- Secure Sockets Layer&lt;/strong&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SSL encrypts web transmissions so they can be securely sent between locations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does not mean that the transmission is totally secure-only the transmission from end to end is safe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;These protocols are designed to be independent from hardware&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Other network protocols&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SMTP&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple mail transfer protocol&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FTP&lt;/strong&gt; - File Transfer protcol&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;host-and-domain-names&#34;&gt;Host and Domain names&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#host-and-domain-names&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;URL holds host and domain names&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Domain name - name of the network that you are trying to connect to&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Host - The computer that you are looking for on that network&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Main domains have lots of different hosts&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Google&amp;rsquo;s main website is served from www, but it also runs other hosts like finance.google.com&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Popular websites have several computers to allow for load balancing and fault tolerance&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One computer can have many host names&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Might be the case if a firm is hosting several websites on a a single piece of computer hardware&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;jackrschumacher.com&#34;&gt;jackrschumacher.com&lt;/a&gt; is the main domain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;uahnotes.jackrschumacher.com&#34;&gt;uahnotes.jackrschumacher.com&lt;/a&gt; is a subdomain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;astra.jackrschumacher.com&#34;&gt;astra.jackrschumacher.com&lt;/a&gt; is a subdomain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can go deeper into subdomains&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Up to 127 levels deep&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most websites are configured to load a default host, in most cases, www&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Host domain names are not case sensitive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can get your own domain name by going through a domain registrar&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Registrars are accredited by ICANN (Internet Corporation for Assigning Names and Numbers)&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Non-profit governance and standards-setting body&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Each registrar may be granted the ability to registrar domain names in one or more top level domains&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some domain names limit registration&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;.edu, .mil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ICANN has also begun to allow people to propose, bin on and secure new top level domains (.berlin, .guru)&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stated that firms that secure the right to generic TLDs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Google and Amazon among others have paid a great deal for their own TLDs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also ccTLDs for two-character country code country domains&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;.uk, .ca, .jp&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be in the country to register in the domain&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Geographic TLDs can be associated with Geographical, geopolitical areas&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;.asia, .scot&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cybersquatting&lt;/strong&gt;  -Knowingly registering a domain name that violates someone else&amp;rsquo;s trademark&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can register lucrative domains and sell later on to corporations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Litigation can be difficult with domains&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;path-name-and-file-name&#34;&gt;Path name and File name&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#path-name-and-file-name&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most web pages end in .html (Hypertext markup language)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;HTML is used to create web pages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Web servers can deliver almost ay type of files&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is always a file behind the scenes even if you do not see it&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paths and file names are case-sensitive&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ip-addresses-and-the-domain-name-system-where-is-it-and-how-do-we-get-there&#34;&gt;IP Addresses and the Domain Name System: “Where Is It? And How Do We Get There?”&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#ip-addresses-and-the-domain-name-system-where-is-it-and-how-do-we-get-there&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-ip-address&#34;&gt;The IP Address&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#the-ip-address&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Every device connected to the internet has an IP adress&#xA;  - **IP address** - A value used to identify a device that is connected to the Internet. IP addresses are usually expressed as four numbers (from 0 to 255), separated by periods.&#xA;  - The internet provider &amp;quot;lends&amp;quot; a device an IP address&#xA;  - The original IP address standard was IPv4 - expressed as a string and 0 and 255&#xA;    - We have run out of IPv4 addresses&#xA;      - Ways to address this through **Network Address Translation**  - Uses a gateway that allows multiple devices to share a single IP address&#xA;      - However, to truly solve this issue, we must switch to IPv6, but this is not backwards compatible with the IPv4 standard&#xA;    - There are schemes to help delay the impact of this IP address drought&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-dns-the-internets-phone-book&#34;&gt;The DNS: The Internet’s Phone Book&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#the-dns-the-internets-phone-book&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Can type the IP address into a Web browser, and the page will show up&#xA;    - Does not help end users that much&#xA;    - DNS helps to prevent this&#xA;      - Basically a phone book that has the IP address associated with a hostname&#xA;      - The phonebook is a nameserver&#xA;    - The resolver does not know everything, but it knows where to start a lookup that will find the address that you are looking for.&#xA;      - Resolver will contact one of 13 root name servers&#xA;        - Acts as a starting place&#xA;        - Does not have one big list, but can point to one of the nameservers for the next level (ex: the .com nameserver)&#xA;        - Will eventually find the IP address of the nameserver of the website/resource&#xA;      - The resolver will remember where it found the nameserver for a while, to ensure quicker delivery to others&#xA;        - Cache is refreshed occasionally to make sure the data remains accurate&#xA;      - This system also ensures that the DNS system is fault-tolerant&#xA;      - ![An example of how DNS works](https://resized-images.flatworldknowledge.com/gallaugher_7-32630/1600/gallaugher_7-32630-fig139.png)&#xA;  -&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-where-youre-going&#34;&gt;Getting Where You’re Going&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#getting-where-youre-going&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tcpip-the-internets-secret-sauce&#34;&gt;TCP/IP: The Internet’s Secret Sauce&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#tcpip-the-internets-secret-sauce&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TCP/IP - also referred to as the internet protocol suite&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Built into any device used to connect to the internet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Operate below http and other applications&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TCP (Transmission Control Protocol)&lt;/strong&gt; - Works at both ends of most Internet communications to ensure a perfect copy of a message is sent.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Web page sliced into packets (datagrams)&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everything on the web is divided into one or more packets&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UDP (User datagram protocol)&lt;/strong&gt; is the less reliable version of TCP used for live streaming media applications where it would be near impossible to achieve the fault tolerance of TCP&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IP (Internet Protocol)&lt;/strong&gt; - Routing protocol that is in charge of forwarding packets on the Internet.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Packets may have to travel over several networks in order to get where they are going&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Done via routers&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Routers speak to each other using IP (they also have IP addresses)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Routers do not have a perfect set of information on all points of the internet, but talk to each other and know the general idea of where to send the packets&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This makes it fault tolerant&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once packets are received by the local machine, TCP checks the validity of the packets and that all packets that have been requested have been received correctly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://resized-images.flatworldknowledge.com/gallaugher_7-32630/1000/gallaugher_7-32630-fig136.png&#34; alt=&#34;TCP/IP example&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;VOIP (Voice over Internet)&lt;/strong&gt; - Removes some of the need to have 2 separate networks - one for phone service and one for regular network&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-connects-the-routers-and-computers&#34;&gt;What Connects the Routers and Computers?&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-connects-the-routers-and-computers&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Local connections are most commonly done with traditional ethernet cables (copper)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Transmissions over longer distances are accomplished via Fiber (typically)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wireless over wifi for shorter distances and over cell phone tower or satellite over longer distances&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;      Laptop to Wifi to base station to LAN to Fiber Optic to ISP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Peering&lt;/strong&gt; - Where different internet service providers connect their equipment in order to share traffic&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Typically done at internet exchange points (IXPs)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some firms also sometimes have Private peering points&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ISPs make money by charging the endpoints of the network (the users) for access to the network&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;last-mile-faster-speed-broader-access&#34;&gt;Last Mile: Faster Speed, Broader Access&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#last-mile-faster-speed-broader-access&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet backbone&lt;/strong&gt; - High-speed data lines provided by many firms all across the world that interconnect and collectively form the core of the Internet.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Backbone transmission speeds are typically now around 100 Gbps&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Increasing speed all the time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Overall network speed is determined by &lt;strong&gt;Amdahl&amp;rsquo;s law&lt;/strong&gt; - A system’s speed is determined by its slowest component.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The bottleneck is the last mile- how customers are able to connect to the internet&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;US is pretty bad in terms of broadband internet access&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bandwidth is bits per second&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cable-broadband&#34;&gt;Cable Broadband&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#cable-broadband&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;90% of US homes are serviced by a cable provider&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coaxial cable&lt;/strong&gt; - Insulated copper cable commonly used by cable television providers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Firms are starting to develop new technologies to replace or substitute coax in order to increase speeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;dsl-phone-company-copper&#34;&gt;DSL: Phone Company Copper&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#dsl-phone-company-copper&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Subscriber line (DSL)&lt;/strong&gt; - Broadband technology that uses the wires of a local telephone network.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Speeds range from 7mbps to 100 mbps (although that is over short distances)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Since this technology uses standard telephone wiring, there is no shielding on the cable, there is no way to prevent signal drop-off&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Only really works well in cities where high-value customers can be accessed over short distances&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Popular in Asia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;fiber-a-light-filled-glass-pipe-to-your-doorstep&#34;&gt;Fiber: A Light-Filled Glass Pipe to Your Doorstep&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#fiber-a-light-filled-glass-pipe-to-your-doorstep&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Also known as FTTH&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fastest last-mile technology&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Works over long distances&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Technology is not already in place&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Most firms build their own fiber network implementation- large costs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;wireless&#34;&gt;Wireless&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#wireless&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mostly delivered through cell towers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wireless spectrum&lt;/strong&gt; - Frequencies used for wireless communication. Most mobile cell phone services have to license spectrum. Some technologies (such as Wi-Fi) use unlicensed public spectrum.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bidding to rights for certain parts of the spectrum by service providers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Need more bandwith&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;T-Mobile arguing for the FCC to set aside more bandwidth for smaller carriers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Increasing amount of content on our phones&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../assets/image_1763332557014_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;Bandwidth required for different types of content&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;5g-a-faster-wireless-network-but-not-all-5g-is-the-same&#34;&gt;5G: A Faster Wireless Network, but Not All 5G Is the Same&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#5g-a-faster-wireless-network-but-not-all-5g-is-the-same&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Speed is related to the wireless spectrum that the firm has licensed&#xA;  - T-Mobile has a large and high speed 5G network due to its usage of the C band, much of which was acquired when it purchased Sprint&#xA;  - Others have struggled because the spectrums that they have may offer good range, but slower speeds&#xA;  - 5G home internet uses satellite dishes instead of phones&#xA;  - UWB vs typical 5G&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;satellite-wireless-and-schemes-to-reach-the-remote&#34;&gt;Satellite Wireless and Schemes to Reach the Remote&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#satellite-wireless-and-schemes-to-reach-the-remote&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - GEO satellite internet&#xA;  - Increasing amount of satellites launched in LEO&#xA;    - Amazon Leo&#xA;    - Starlink&#xA;  - However, the cost of this service is significant&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;wi-fi-and-other-hotspots&#34;&gt;Wi-Fi and Other Hotspots&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#wi-fi-and-other-hotspots&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;  - Needs to be in range of the base station or hotspot&#xA;    - Typically around 300 feet&#xA;  - Wi-Fi equipped mobile devices can sometimes act as their own personal hotspot&#xA;  - Bluetooth as a replacement for speaker cables and the like&#xA;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;net-neutrality-whats-fair&#34;&gt;Net Neutrality: What&amp;rsquo;s Fair?&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#net-neutrality-whats-fair&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Net Neutrality&lt;/strong&gt; - The principle that all Internet traffic should be treated equally, and ISPs should not discriminate, slow down access, or charge differentially by user, content, site, platform, application, type of attached equipment, or modes of communication.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Google believes that ISPs should not be entitled to control activity online&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ISPs could restrict content (ex: Comcast restricting content streamed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A continuing US policy discussion over the last several years&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;to-infinity-and-beyond-spacex-starlink-and-the-awesome-power-wielded-by-elon-musks-firms&#34;&gt;To Infinity and Beyond: SpaceX Starlink and the Awesome Power Wielded by Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s Firms&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#to-infinity-and-beyond-spacex-starlink-and-the-awesome-power-wielded-by-elon-musks-firms&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Many firms have failed at the promise of creating global broadband&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Iridium went bankrupt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The One World consortium had to be bailed out by the British government and later acquired by French firm Eutelsat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Musk is the only one who has delivered on his promise of global-spanning broadband&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Older satellite constellations orbited in GEO&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Geosynchronous Earth Orbit. GEO satellites orbit the Earth at a fixed position, roughly 22,000 miles (35,000 km) above the Earth—roughly the same distance as the Earth&amp;rsquo;s circumference. This distance means fewer satellites can cover a larger geographic distance, but it also increases latency due to the time taken to send a signal from ground antennas to satellites and back.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink satellites orbit in LEO&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Low Earth Orbit. LEO satellites orbit the Earth at a range of less than 1,200 miles (2,000 km), and may be significantly less (Starlink satellites are about 340 miles or 550km up). A closer distance means more satellites are needed to cover a smaller geographic broadcast/receive footprint, and that satellites will regularly move in and out of range above a given point, so most LEO efforts deploy many more satellites than their GEO counterparts. The big advantage of LEO over GEO is speed—with latency being smaller, transmission speeds are much faster than GEO efforts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink satellites orbit makes the signal transmission time take 1/60th of the time&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink is so fast that it is considered to be an alternative for some ground based networks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink satellites are not in a fixed position, but rather pass signals to each each other using lasers&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink satellites are about the size of a couch, unlike GEO satellites that are the size of school busses&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink currently has approximately 9,000 satellites in orbit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../assets/image_1763413217627_0.png&#34; alt=&#34;image.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is a lot of room between the satellites in orbit&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;SpaceX taps into the US Governments Space Debris Collision Detection System&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink satellites have enough propulsion to move itself out of orbit when it has exceed it useful life&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Satellite typically last around 3.5 years before they are deorbited&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Solar events can lead to early reentry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Worry about a collision that may lead to a cascading catastrophe&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kessler effect&lt;/strong&gt; - A feared cascading effect when colliding space debris hits existing objects, creating additional debris and additional collisions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;42 million people in the rural United States that lack access to high-speed broadband&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 billion people are not online yet in the world&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Starlink is not cheap - $600 for equipment, $99/month of unlimited&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Much of SpaceX&amp;rsquo;s evaluation is driven by the future success of Starlink&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;T-Mobile and Starlink to cover gaps in the networks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Already used widely throughout the world, especially in areas torn apart by war, or by natural disasters&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ukraine war - 42,000 terminals&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Has used geofencing to prevent Starlink use outside of the current theater of conflict&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Geofencing&lt;/strong&gt; - A geofence is a virtual perimeter around a physical location. Geofencing is often used to send alerts when a device is detected within or outside an area of intended operation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Concern about &amp;ldquo;overcrowding&amp;rdquo; in space&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Especially from China and countries where free speech is suppressed and the deployment of Starlink in their countries might allow for unrestricted speech&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-3-strategy-and-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-3-strategy-and-technology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainable competitive advantage:&lt;/strong&gt; Financial performance that consistently outperforms industry averages.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational effectiveness:&lt;/strong&gt; Performing the same tasks better than rivals perform them.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commodity:&lt;/strong&gt; A basic good that can be interchanged with nearly identical offerings by others—think milk, coal, orange juice, or, to a lesser extent, Windows PCs and Android phones. The more commoditized an offering, the greater the likelihood that competition will be based on price.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast follower problem:&lt;/strong&gt; Exists when savvy rivals watch a pioneer’s efforts, learn from their successes and missteps, then enter the market quickly with a comparable or superior product at a lower cost before the first mover can dominate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Augmented-reality:&lt;/strong&gt; A technology that superimposes content, such as images and animation, on top of real-world images.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strategic positioning:&lt;/strong&gt; Performing different tasks than rivals, or the same tasks in a different way.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resource-based view of competitive advantage:&lt;/strong&gt; The strategic thinking approach suggesting that if a firm is to maintain sustainable competitive advantage, it must control an exploitable resource, or set of resources, that have four critical characteristics. These resources must be (1) valuable, (2) rare, (3) imperfectly imitable, and (4) nonsubstitutable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dense wave division multiplexing (DWDM):&lt;/strong&gt; A technology that increases the transmission capacity (and hence speed) of fiber-optic cable. Transmissions using fiber are accomplished by transmitting light inside “glass” cables. In DWDM, the light inside fiber is split into different wavelengths in a way similar to how a prism splits light into different colors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imitation-resistant value chain:&lt;/strong&gt; A way of doing business that competitors struggle to replicate and that frequently involves technology in a key enabling role.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Value chain:&lt;/strong&gt; The set of activities through which a product or service is created and delivered to customers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Straddled:&lt;/strong&gt; In strategic management, this refers to a firm&amp;rsquo;s attempt to occupy more than one position, while failing to match the benefits of a more efficient, singularly focused rival.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brand:&lt;/strong&gt; The symbolic embodiment of all the information connected with a product or service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viral marketing:&lt;/strong&gt; Leveraging consumers to promote a product or service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scale advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Advantages related to size.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economies of scale:&lt;/strong&gt; When costs can be spread across increasing units of production or in serving multiple customers. Businesses that have favorable economies of scale (like many Internet firms) are sometimes referred to as being highly scalable.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network effects:&lt;/strong&gt; Also known as Metcalfe’s Law, or network externalities. When the value of a product or service increases as its number of users expands.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bundling:&lt;/strong&gt; Selling products available separately as a single package. Bundling can be especially effective when a software product or service is included with a hardware product. Bundling can also be tricky as it can raise a risk of unfair competitive practices, especially if a firm has a monopoly or otherwise large amount of market control.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APIs:&lt;/strong&gt; Programming hooks, or guidelines, published by firms that tell other programs how to get a service to perform a task such as send or receive data. For example, Amazon provides APIs to let developers write their own applications and websites that can send the firm orders.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affiliates:&lt;/strong&gt; Third parties that promote a product or service, typically in exchange for a cut of any sales.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-practicing entities:&lt;/strong&gt; Commonly known as patent trolls, these firms make money by acquiring and asserting patents, rather than bringing products and services to market.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private:&lt;/strong&gt; As in “to go private” or “take a firm private.” Buying up a publicly traded firm’s shares. Usually done when a firm has suffered financially and when a turnaround strategy will first yield losses that would further erode share price. Firms (often called private equity, buyout, LBO, or leveraged buyout firms) that take another company private hope to improve results so that the company can be sold to another firm or they can reissue shares on public markets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Porter’s five forces:&lt;/strong&gt; Also known as Industry and Competitive Analysis. A framework considering the interplay between (1) the intensity of rivalry among existing competitors, (2) the threat of new entrants, (3) the threat of substitute goods or services, (4) the bargaining power of buyers, and (5) the bargaining power of suppliers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price transparency:&lt;/strong&gt; The degree to which complete information is available.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information asymmetry:&lt;/strong&gt; A decision situation where one party has more or better information than its counterparty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-5--netflix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-5--netflix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-introduction-the-great-pivot&#34;&gt;1. Introduction: The Great Pivot&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#1-introduction-the-great-pivot&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Netflix is a rare example of a firm that disrupted itself to survive. Under CEO Reed Hastings, the firm transitioned from a DVD-by-mail giant (which obliterated Blockbuster) to the global leader in streaming.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Statistics (as of Fall 2023):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscribers:&lt;/strong&gt; 247 million globally.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reach:&lt;/strong&gt; Available in every country except China, Syria, North Korea, and Russia.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Engagement:&lt;/strong&gt; In the U.S., Netflix beats Hulu by a factor of &amp;gt;3 in teen viewership.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resilience:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite competition from Disney and Warner Bros., Netflix stock gained 45% in 2023 while rivals struggled.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-atoms-to-bits-the-economic-shift&#34;&gt;2. Atoms to Bits: The Economic Shift&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#2-atoms-to-bits-the-economic-shift&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The transition from physical media (&amp;ldquo;atoms&amp;rdquo;) to digital streaming (&amp;ldquo;bits&amp;rdquo;) fundamentally changed the business mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-6-moores-law-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-6-moores-law-and-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moore’s Law:&lt;/strong&gt; Chip performance per dollar doubles every eighteen months.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microprocessor:&lt;/strong&gt; The part of the computer that executes the instructions of a computer program.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Latency:&lt;/strong&gt; In computing, latency means delay. Low-latency tasks have less delay, so they are faster.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random-access memory (RAM):&lt;/strong&gt; The fast, chip-based volatile storage in a computing device.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Volatile memory:&lt;/strong&gt; Storage (such as RAM chips) that is wiped clean when power is cut off from a device.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonvolatile memory:&lt;/strong&gt; Storage that retains data even when powered down (such as flash memory, hard disc, or DVD storage).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flash memory:&lt;/strong&gt; Nonvolatile, chip-based storage, often used in mobile phones, cameras, and MP3 players. Sometimes called flash RAM, flash memory is slower than conventional RAM but holds its charge even when the power goes out.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solid state electronics:&lt;/strong&gt; Semiconductor-based devices. Solid state components often suffer fewer failures and require less energy than mechanical counterparts because they have no moving parts. RAM, flash memory, and microprocessors are solid state devices. Hard drives are not.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSD:&lt;/strong&gt; Solid state drive- a chip based, novolatile storage device.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semiconductors:&lt;/strong&gt; A substance such as silicon dioxide used inside most computer chips that is capable of enabling as well as inhibiting the flow of electricity. From a managerial perspective, when someone refers to semiconductors, they are talking about computer chips, and the semiconductor industry is the chip business.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optical fiber line:&lt;/strong&gt; A high-speed glass or plastic-lined networking cable used in telecommunications.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price elasticity:&lt;/strong&gt; The rate at which the demand for a product or service fluctuates with price change. Goods and services that are highly price elastic (e.g., most consumer electronics) see demand spike as prices drop, whereas goods and services that are less price elastic are less responsive to price change (think heart surgery).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet of Things (IoT):&lt;/strong&gt; A vision where low-cost sensors, processors, and communication are embedded into a wide array of products and our environment, allowing a vast network to collect data, analyze input, and automatically coordinate collective action.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fabs:&lt;/strong&gt; Semiconductor fabrication facilities; the multibillion-dollar plants used to manufacture semiconductors.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silicon wafers:&lt;/strong&gt; A thin, circular slice of material used to create semiconductor devices. Hundreds of chips may be etched on a single wafer, where they are eventually cut out for individual packaging.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multicore microprocessors:&lt;/strong&gt; Microprocessors with two or more (typically lower power) calculating processor cores on the same piece of silicon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Supercomputers:&lt;/strong&gt; Computers that are among the fastest of any in the world at the time of their introduction.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massively parallel:&lt;/strong&gt; Computers designed with many microprocessors that work together, simultaneously, to solve problems.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grid computing:&lt;/strong&gt; A type of computing that uses special software to enable several, often idle computers to work together on a common problem, as if they were a massively parallel supercomputer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cluster computing:&lt;/strong&gt; Connecting server computers via software and networking so that their resources can be used to collectively solve computing tasks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software as a service (SaaS):&lt;/strong&gt; A form of cloud computing where a firm subscribes to a third-party software and receives a service that is delivered online.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud computing:&lt;/strong&gt; Replacing computing resources—either an organization’s or individual’s hardware or software—with services provided over the Internet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server farms:&lt;/strong&gt; A massive network of computer servers running software to coordinate their collective use. Server farms provide the infrastructure backbone to SaaS and hardware cloud efforts, as well as many large-scale Internet services.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E-waste:&lt;/strong&gt; Discarded, often obsolete technology; also known as electronic waste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-7--disruptive-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-7--disruptive-technologies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disruptive innovations:&lt;/strong&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t need to perform better than incumbents, they simply need to perform well enough to appeal to the customers of the incumbents (and often do so at a lower price).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why do large firms sometimes fail?:&lt;/strong&gt; Large firms often do not see new technologies as adding value to their business, and therefore do not invest in the innovation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can a firm recognize potentially disruptive technology?:&lt;/strong&gt; Pay attention to the trajectory of fast and cheap technological advancement as well as new and emerging technology. It&amp;rsquo;s important to converse with those on the experimental edge of technology.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transition costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Even for firms that are well armed for a battle with an emergent and disruptive newcomer, a transition from old models to new can be costly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additive manufacturing:&lt;/strong&gt; A type of industrial 3D printing where material is built up, layer by layer, as material is progressively added to shape an object.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin:&lt;/strong&gt; An open source, decentralized payment system (sometimes controversially referred to as a digital, virtual, or cryptocurrency) that operates in a peer-to-peer environment, without bank or central authority.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cryptocurrency:&lt;/strong&gt; A digital asset where a secure form of mathematics (cryptography) is used to handle transactions, control the creation of additional units, and verify the transfer of assets. Cryptocurrencies usually take advantage of a technology known as a blockchain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain:&lt;/strong&gt; A distributed and decentralized ledger that records and verifies transactions and ownership, making it difficult to tamper with or shut down.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeFi:&lt;/strong&gt; A distributed and decentralized ledger that records and verifies transactions and ownership, making it difficult to tamper with or shut down.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CBDC:&lt;/strong&gt; A digital form of a government-issued currency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stablecoins:&lt;/strong&gt; Cryptocurrencies that have their value pegged to a currency or commodity, rather than have currency value float independently.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crypto benefits:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s often thought that cryptocurrencies could be a boon for international commerce, especially for cross-border remittance and in expanding e-commerce in emerging markets.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consumer benefit:&lt;/strong&gt; For cryptocurrencies, consumer benefit needs to be stronger.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-9--amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/semester-3/is-301/class-notes/chapter-9--amazon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;81-introduction-the-scale-of-the-everything-store&#34;&gt;8.1 Introduction: The Scale of the &amp;ldquo;Everything Store&amp;rdquo;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#81-introduction-the-scale-of-the-everything-store&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite early skepticism (dubbed &amp;ldquo;Amazon.toast&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Amazon.bomb&amp;rdquo;), Amazon has evolved from an online bookstore into a global dominant force.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financials:&lt;/strong&gt; Amazon is the second company (after Apple) to reach a $1 trillion market cap. It generates reliable profits, largely driven by AWS and advertising, rather than just retail margins.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope:&lt;/strong&gt; Amazon accounts for roughly &lt;strong&gt;50% of every $1 spent on retail e-commerce&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-Party Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Third-party sellers make up &lt;strong&gt;60%&lt;/strong&gt; of Amazon’s retail sales. Amazon handles logistics/fees for these sellers, often taking ~50% of the seller&amp;rsquo;s revenue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Employment:&lt;/strong&gt; Amazon is the nation&amp;rsquo;s second-largest private employer (behind Walmart), having hired city-sized populations during the pandemic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Founder Jeff Bezos emphasized a 5-to-7-year investment horizon (vs. the standard 3-year corporate view), prioritizing long-term market leadership over short-term profits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;82-the-emperor-of-e-commerce-strategy--operations&#34;&gt;8.2 The Emperor of E-commerce: Strategy &amp;amp; Operations&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#82-the-emperor-of-e-commerce-strategy--operations&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Amazon’s competitive advantage is built on the &amp;ldquo;Wheel of Growth&amp;rdquo;: &lt;strong&gt;Selection, Customer Experience, and Low Prices&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
